

# **ABOUT**

Howdy! I'm a designer and creative technologist with over five years of experience building web applications that focus on accessibility and ease of maintenance. I am currently working on the capstone of my Google UX Design certification and am interested in using my design and engineering knowledge in tandem to produce creative, equity-focused work. I'm also an illustrator, an avid language learner, and a virgo.

**Current Freelance Projects:** Screen reader friendly PDF design with custom vector graphics, portfolio website redesign and build, graphic and social media design, and visual branding for a podcast.

# **SKILLS + TECHNOLOGIES**

**Design:** Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe XD, Adobe InDesign, Adobe AfterEffects, Figma, Procreate, Sketch, Spline

**Code:** Javascript, React.js, CSS, SASS, Git, Liquid, HTML, GSAP, PHP, styled-components, three.js, Frontity, GatsbyJS, Gulp, JQuery, WebGL, Shopify, Webpack, Wordpress

## **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Automic Gold**

Front End Engineer (July 2021-present)

Maintains a smooth, functional ecommerce experience through routine bug fixes, addition of new features, styling updates, and performance and accessibility audits.

Reviews and provides feedback for all design updates prior to build to ensure new features are equitable, intuitive to use, and ADA compliant. Currently using three.js to develop a tool which will allow users to instantly preview 3D models of custom jewelry.

#### Santoro Design

Designer-Developer, Consultant (Oct 2020 - present)

Authored, distributed, and presented user research to improve team understanding of specialized project needs for niche user communities

Reviewed 100% of project assets and UX flows to ensure full ADA compliance and advised on strategies that streamlined user experience.

#### known.creative

Senior Front End Engineer (Jan 2016 - June 2021)

Streamlined development workflow by 20% while improving output quality by engineering a boilerplate Wordpress theme on which all agency projects were initiated thereafter.

Brought accessibility awareness to agency by establishing procedure ensuring minimum A level ADA compliance on all projects.

Established technical support flow between engineers and clients, streamlining the ticketing process and improving code extensibility through direct communications regarding project requirements.

Increased cross-departmental understanding at handoff by collaborating in the UX phase and enforcing accessibility standards in design reviews.

Produced illustrative assets for client packaging, promotional materials, and ebooks.

## **EDUCATION**

### Google UX Design Certificate (96% avg.)

Ongoing, 6/7 Courses Complete

**Focus:** Accessibility, Usability Testing, UX Research, Wireframing, Protoyping, UI Design, Design Thinking, Equitable Design

### **Smith College (3.85/4.0)**

B.A. Government, Chinese - (2009-2013)

**Honors:** First Group Scholar (graduation within top 10% of class), Ettie Chin Hong Prize (excellence in the study of East Asian Language), Dean's List